# 福建·厦门
Xiamen, Fujian Province
# 哈喽 现在是早上起来八点钟
Hello, it’s 8 o’clock in the morning now
# 我打算到旁边的沙茶面馆
I’m planning to go to the Satay Noodle Shop next door
# 吃一碗
To have a bowl of satay noodles
# 就是前面这个了
Here we are, it’s right in front of us
# 人好像还不是特别多
There are not that many people now
# 走吧
Let's go!
# （看下价格）
(Checking the price)
# 阿姨 我 我要一个18块钱的
Hi aunty, I’ll have a bowl of the 18-yuan noodles
# 我要一个18块钱的
I want one of the 18-yuan noodles
# 面馆这边差不多有5口锅
There are about 5 pots here
# 一口锅放了罗汉肉
There are some pork belly in one pot
# 一口锅放了沙茶底汤
In that one is the satay stock
# 还有一口锅放的卤豆腐
Tofu in Lushui (Chinese master stock) is in another pot
# 还有一口锅是用来汆熟面条的
This pot is for quick boiling the noodles
# 还有呢 就是一锅的肉粽
The last pot is full of zongzi (aka rice dumplings) with pork stuffing
# 咱们这个是要的18块钱的基础版
This is what I ordered, the basic version which costs 18 yuan
# 你可以看到沙茶面的汤底特别浓郁
As you can see, the soup of these satay noodles is very rich
# 泛着微微的红色
It’s in light red colour
# 可能是橘色
Or maybe it’s orange
# 因为汤是沙茶卤汤
This is because the soup is made from satay stock
# 咱们要的这一碗是18块钱的
Inside this 18-yuan bowl we ordered
# 里面是加了罗汉肉、鱼丸、豆腐泡
There are some pork belly, fish balls, puffed tofu
# 还有面条
Some noodles
# 加了一些豆芽
And some bean sprouts
# 最后呢 就是舀了一勺蒜末
Last but not least, a spoonful of crushed garlic
# 来了厦门两次 今天总算吃了一碗
I have come to Xiamen twice, and finally I had the chance to get one of these
# 不过 我吃这边的面条就是 没有很筋道
Although the noodles here are not that al-dente
# 就是 一咬就断
It means that you can easily break them by one bite
# 它这个汤就是微甜
The soup is slightly sweet
# 还有点辣
And a little bit spicy
# 我觉得沙茶面 如果不加肉
In my opinion, even if no meats are added to the satay noodles
# 直接是面 加沙茶底汤
Basically, just noodles in the satay stock
# 也是很不错的
It can also be quite good
# 这个汤会让你觉得，很下面
As this soup can really lift your appetite to eat the noodles
# 鱼丸吃起来 就是比较清淡
On the other hand, these fish balls are very mild in taste
# 口感上比较紧实
And firm in texture
# 它里面是有猪肉的
They are stuffed with some pork
# 它这个豆腐应该是炸过的吧
The tofu should have been deep fried
# 还是能够吸收一定的汤汁的
So it can absorb decent a amount of soup
# 它这个豆腐 外面虽然说是金黄色的
The tofu is golden on the outside
# 但是里面就像卤水豆腐一样
But inside, it’s like Lushui tofu
# 没有很多孔
There are not that many holes
# 还是比较柔嫩的
And it’s quite tender
# 它这个小店就是 完全靠几个阿姨做起来的店
The fame of this little shop is completely built up by these aunties
# 而且是什么
And you know what
# 很多人来中山路这边旅游
A lot of people travelling to Zhongshan Road
# 可能就会选择这家沙茶面
Will end up in this Satay Noodle Shop
# 我两次来这边 这边每次都是人很多
I’ve been here twice, and it is always full of diners every time I come
# 今天总算尝到了沙茶面的味道
Today, I eventually had this opportunity to taste these noodles
# 主要是起了个大早 而且
Mostly because I came here rather early in the morning, and
# 酒店又没有吃的
There was no food provided in my hotel
# 到这边来吃碗沙茶面 也不错
It feels great to come here to have a bowl of the satay noodles
# 你看 这沙茶汤
Look at this satay stock
# 等下人排队
# 你看 这沙茶汤
Wait, get in line!
Look at this satay stock
# 沙茶汤 一直不够用啊
There has never been enough of satay stock
# 到中午还得煮好多锅
Need to cook many pots till noon
# 看我切猪肝
Watch me slicing these pork livers
# 我们切猪肝 切30多年了
We have been slicing pork livers for more than 30 years
# 哈哈哈
[laughters]
# 猪肝 试试看 好香的
Try these pork livers, they taste really good
# 吃几片猪肝吧 好嫩的
Have a bite, they are very tender
# 我烫一点给你们试试看
I’ll quick boil some for you to try
# 不用 真不用
No no, that's too generous
# 不要紧的 真的
It’s ok, seriously
# 试试看 不要吃多 一点就好
Have a go, you don’t need to eat much, just a little bit
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 真的很好吃
They are truly tasty
# 和阿姨聊了一会儿天
I had some chats with the aunty there
# 阿姨说 你们尝尝我们这边的猪肝吧
She insisted that we should try some of their pork livers
# 然后 她就是
Then
# 汆了一下几片猪肝还有罗汉肉给我们吃
She blanched a few pieces of pork liver with some pork belly for us
# 我们尝尝吧
Let’s have a try
# 这么汆熟的好嫩啊
They are so tender by blanching like this
# 阿姨说 切猪肝切了30多年
The aunty said she had been slicing pork livers for 30 years
# 现在能够达到的水平就是 切到厚薄均匀
And she had reached the level of slicing them into evenly thick pieces
# 这个沙茶底汤真的是爱了
I absolutely love this satay soup
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
Follow China Food Travel